<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sarah Campbell</title>
    <link>/./</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sarah Campbell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequence Alignment with Python</title>
      <link>/./posts/theme-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./posts/theme-demo/</guid>
      <description>Nucleotide sequence alignment can be tedious to code by hand, but thanks to services like BLAST and the Python package biopython, understanding the alignment process is not necessary for producing parsimonious alignments. Even though hand-coding isn&#39;t the quickest method, understanding traditional algorithms can clear up how modern programs work and aid in troubleshooting. I&#39;ll go over a common global alignment algorithm, the Needleman-Wunsch algorithm.
Needleman-Wunsch algorithm This is a global alignment algorithm, identifying the best alignment after considering each residue within the entire sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/./post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/./about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am an undergraduate student completing a bachelor&#39;s degree in Neuroscience from the University of Texas at Austin.
My scientific work looks at the molecular basis of social behavior in paper wasps and cichlid fish, and relates these findings to a broader evolutionary and ecological context. I&#39;m also invested in determining how the scientific community can better reinforce trust with the public, particularly through narrative storytelling.
When I&#39;m not doing science, you can find me field sketching, baking, or backpacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/./contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./contact/</guid>
      <description>連絡をとりたいですか? 質問や報告などの連絡は下記からお願いします。
 open an issue on GitHub ask me on Twitter  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/./contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./contact/</guid>
      <description>Want Contact? Have questions or suggestions? Feel free to open an issue on GitHub or ask me on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>/./cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./cv/</guid>
      <description>EDUCATION The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX | Expected May 2020
Bachelor of Science and Arts in Neuroscience, Honors
Certificate in Evidence and Inquiry
Current GPA 3.96/4.00  RESEARCH INTERESTS My primary interests lie in the field of neuroethology, specifically in the molecular basis of social behavior, problem-solving behaviors, and auditory communication. Broadly, my research in this area focuses on how the environment modulates social behavior in various study models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EDA with Birds</title>
      <link>/./edawriteup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./edawriteup/</guid>
      <description>10/20/2019
Exploratory Data Analysis: What’s Going on with Birds? 0. Introduction In this report, I will be examining NCRN Bird Monitoring Datasets from 2007-2018. These datasets report sightings of forest (and beginning in 2014, grassland) birds across 11 U.S. national parks in the Naitonal Capital Region, recorded twice per year at every site. Each dataset represents one park’s records from 2007-2017, with some parks contributing an additional dataset for 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Modeling</title>
      <link>/./project_ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./project_ii/</guid>
      <description>11/26/2019
Modeling, Testing, and Predicting Hawk Data 0. Introduction data(Hawks) head(Hawks) ## Month Day Year CaptureTime ReleaseTime BandNumber Species Age Sex Wing ## 1 9 19 1992 13:30 877-76317 RT I 385 ## 2 9 22 1992 10:30 877-76318 RT I 376 ## 3 9 23 1992 12:45 877-76319 RT I 381 ## 4 9 23 1992 10:50 745-49508 CH I F 265 ## 5 9 27 1992 11:15 1253-98801 SS I F 205 ## 6 9 28 1992 11:25 1207-55910 RT I 412 ## Weight Culmen Hallux Tail StandardTail Tarsus WingPitFat KeelFat Crop ## 1 920 25.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/./projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/./projects/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory Data Analysis in R Trialing exploratory analysis techniques in R on an extensive bird observation dataset.
    Characterizing the Paper Wasp Diet Creating a nutritional profile of the Polistes exclamans diet.
    Effects of Entertainment Media on the Public Perception of Science How does science in television and film affect how we view science and the scientific community?
    Linear Modeling Linear modeling techniques applied to the Hawks dataset from the R package Stats2Data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>